LEIF HUHN

San Francisco, CA 94102 code.gardener@leifhuhn.com (415) 343-5343

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dev-ops developer with over 15 years of experience in IT. Experience in a wide variety of technologies and platforms. Particular strengths in maintaining Linux servers and automating processes using Perl scripting. Initiated infrastructure improvements as well as new programming methodologies and systems. Motivated self-starter and enthusiastic team member.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Lead
Riverbed Technology

2010 – Present San Francisco, CA

- · Mentored junior coders.
- · Oversaw maintenance of critical pieces of our testing infrastructure.
- · Conceived of, collaboratively designed, and oversaw development of an automated program "Rack-and-Roll," greatly simplifying the process of adding new hardware into the lab.
- · Created system to power down unused testing machines, saving power, cooling, and money.
- · Automated VMWare vCenter to automate the installation and testing of VMs.
- · Troubleshot various DHCP, TFTP, and PXE networking problems using Cisco, Force10, and commodity hardware.
- · Troubleshot a myriad of problems with internal appliance manufacturing. These problems had various root causes, such as bugs in the unreleased product, bugs in the build system, hardware problems, user error, networking problems, service outages, etc.
- · Integrated new products into our existing test and networking infrastructure.
- · Used puppet to automate system administration tasks.
- · Moved existing Perl web app to PersistentPerl, greatly improving performance.
- · Documented new and existing procedures.
- Refactored testing codebase for greater maintainability.
- · Made OO design decisions for future direction of testing codebase.
- · Participated in the code review process.

System Administrator

2003 - 2010

Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

Berkeley, CA

- Installed, maintained, and updated Linux and Windows servers providing critical infrastructure (mail, web, dns, nfs, mysql, iptables, RAID, LVM, and ssh).
- Reduced our server footprint by 60% by migrating applications from legacy versions of BSD and SunOS to Linux, thereby saving on licensing costs.
- Used VMWare to create Windows server on existing Linux server to provide essential services that were only rarely required, thereby saving the cost of having another server.
- · Managed remote servers for multiple law firms. Worked with system administrators from client companies to resolve networking problems.
- · Transitioned our systems to 64-bit to allow processing of larger datasets.
- · Evaluated server workloads and made purchasing decisions.

- · Hired and oversaw contractors to upgrade data and phone wiring.
- Used Nagios to provide 24/7/365 monitoring of critical services.
- · Utilized intrusion prevention and detection software to maintain security (Snort).
- · Responsible for migrating data obtained through legal discovery into our systems (i.e. from Oracle, PostreSQL, etc).
- · Provided desktop support for the local office.
- · Used scripting to automate backup processes.

Web Developer

2001 - 2003

Drogin, Kakiqi & Associates

Berkeley, CA

- Developed Model-View-Controller web framework with a MySQL backend tailored for the specific needs of the company.
- · Created websites to allow hundreds of paralegals from around the country to work together to interview thousands of plaintiffs in large class action lawsuits.
- · Oversaw and trained junior web developers.
- · Wrote perl programs to process data in legacy formats.
- · Met with clients to deliver sales presentations.

Web Developer

1999 - 2000

Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission

Tallahassee, FL

- · Developed data aware client side web applications.
- Increased productivity through the creation of a system for dynamically tracking bird migration patterns thereby freeing an analyst from writing weekly reports.
- · Managed IIS web servers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Perl, Python, C/C++, Java
- · XML, HTML, SQL, CGI
- Apache, IIS
- · MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- · Cisco IOS, Force10 FTOS
- · Puppet, Linux, BSD, Solaris
- Sendmail, DNS
- Icinga, Nagios, Snort
- · RAID, LVM, NFS

- tcpdump, wireshark
- Unix Scripting: bash, tcsh, expect
- Windows Deployment, Hyper-V, cygwin, Power-shell
- · OS X
- · VMWare ESX, vCenter
- · KVM
- IAT_FX

EDUCATION & HOBBIES

- · University of California, Berkeley, CA
- Bachelors Degree in Physics
- · Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL

Completed University Honors Program

GPA: 3.9

- · Conversational in American Sign Language
- · Home automation including a web dashboard at home using a Ruby / CoffeeScript framework running on a RaspberryPi 2.